<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>



    <string-array name="biceps_head">

        <item>Chin Ups</item>
        <item>Barbbell Curl</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Curl</item>
        <item>Hammer Curl</item>
        <item>Concentration Curl</item>
        <item>Reverse Curl</item>
        <item>Incline Dumbbell Curl</item>
        <item>Prechar Curl</item>
        <item>High Pulley Curl</item>
    </string-array>



    <string-array name="biceps_content">
        <item>Chinups are Pullups using a supinated grip.\n
            You grip the bar with your palms facing up instead of down.You then pull yourself up. Chinups are easier than Pullups because they use your biceps more.
            They use more muscle.
            \n\nIf you can’t do a single Pullup, try Chinups instead.
            If you want bigger arms, do Chinups.
            \n\nNote that Chinups work your upper-back muscles too. It just uses more biceps.
            \n\nTechnique on Chinups is same as on Pullups.
            \nYour hands should be shoulder-width apart.
            \nA wider grip shortens the range of motion.It also rotates your arms more out.
            \n\nThis stresses your wrists, elbows and shoulders.It can cause pain. Grip the bar narrow.
            \nYour hands should be just outside your shoulders when your chin passes the bar at the top.
            If Chinups feel uncomfortable because you’re inflexible, stick with Pullups.
        </item>


        <item>Stand up with your torso upright while holding a barbell at a shoulder-width grip. The palm of your hands should be facing forward and the elbows should be close to the torso. This will be your starting position.
              \n\nWhile holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Tip: Only the forearms should move.
              \n\nContinue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a second and squeeze the biceps hard.
              \n\nSlowly begin to bring the bar back to starting position as your breathe in.
              \n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Step 1:Stand up straight with legs shoulder-width apart or sit on a bench. If you\'re sitting on a bench, make sure your head, shoulders and butt are in contact with the bench with your feet firmly on the ground.
              \n\nStep 2:Hold a dumbbell in each hand. Make sure your thumbs are curled around the grips. Hold the dumbbells by your sides, palms facing forward. Keep your back straight and shoulders rolled back and down.
              \n\nStep 3:Bend your elbows and slowly bring the dumbbells up to your chest while breathing out. Keep your elbows by your sides and don’t arch your back. Make sure your wrists are in line with your elbows and keep your shoulders straight.
              \n\nStep 4:Breathe in as you lower the dumbbells away from your chest back to the starting position. Maintain a slow and controlled movement as you straighten your elbows. That\'s one rep. Aim for two to three sets of eight to 12 repetitions (lifts). Increase the weight when the repetitions become easier to perform.
              \n\nStep 5:You can work the biceps more by holding the dumbbells at the starting position with your palms facing in toward your sides. As you bring the dumbbells up, twist your wrist and forearm up so the dumbbells ends facing your chest. As you bring the dumbbells down, twist your wrists and forearms back toward your sides as your arms come to rest.
        </item>


        <item>Stand up with your torso upright and a dumbbell on each hand being held at arms length. The elbows should be close to the torso.
\n\nThe palms of the hands should be facing your torso. This will be your starting position.
\nn\nNow, while holding your upper arm stationary, exhale and curl the weight forward while contracting the biceps. Continue to raise the weight until the biceps are fully contracted and the dumbbell is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a brief moment as you squeeze the biceps. Tip: Focus on keeping the elbow stationary and only moving your forearm.
\n\nAfter the brief pause, inhale and slowly begin the lower the dumbbells back down to the starting position.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Sit down on a flat bench with one dumbbell in front of you between your legs. Your legs should be spread with your knees bent and feet on the floor.
\n\nUse your right arm to pick the dumbbell up. Place the back of your right upper arm on the top of your inner right thigh. Rotate the palm of your hand until it is facing forward away from your thigh. Tip: Your arm should be extended and the dumbbell should be above the floor. This will be your starting position.
\n\nWhile holding the upper arm stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Only the forearms should move. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the dumbbells are at shoulder level. Tip: At the top of the movement make sure that the little finger of your arm is higher than your thumb. This guarantees a good contraction. Hold the contracted position for a second as you squeeze the biceps.
\n\nSlowly begin to bring the dumbbells back to starting position as your breathe in. Caution: Avoid swinging motions at any time.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions. Then repeat the movement with the left arm.</item>


        <item>Stand up with your torso upright while holding a barbell at shoulder width with the elbows close to the torso. The palm of your hands should be facing down (pronated grip). This will be your starting position.
\n\nWhile holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Only the forearms should move. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a second as you squeeze the muscle.
\n\nSlowly begin to bring the bar back to starting position as your breathe in.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Sit back on an incline bench with a dumbbell in each hand held at arms length. Keep your elbows close to your torso and rotate the palms of your hands until they are facing forward. This will be your starting position.
\n\nWhile holding the upper arm stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Only the forearms should move. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the dumbbells are at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a second.
\n\nSlowly begin to bring the dumbbells back to starting position as your breathe in.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>To perform this movement you will need a preacher bench and an E-Z bar. Grab the E-Z curl bar at the close inner handle (either have someone hand you the bar which is preferable or grab the bar from the front bar rest provided by most preacher benches). The palm of your hands should be facing forward and they should be slightly tilted inwards due to the shape of the bar.
\n\nWith the upper arms positioned against the preacher bench pad and the chest against it, hold the E-Z Curl Bar at shoulder length. This will be your starting position.
\n\nAs you breathe in, slowly lower the bar until your upper arm is extended and the biceps is fully stretched.
\n\nAs you exhale, use the biceps to curl the weight up until your biceps is fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder height. Squeeze the biceps hard and hold this position for a second.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Set a dual pulley system to a high position on both sides.
\n\nGrasp a single grip attachment on both sides, and turn your hands upward.
\n\nKeeping your upper arms about parallel with horizontal (i.e. the ground), your wrists neutral in position, and your palms facing upward, curl the weight toward each of your temples with both arms, and exhale throughout the movement.Once the attachment grips reach your temples, briefly squeeze your biceps with both arms to achieve extra emphasis on their peaks.
\n\nLower the weight until your arms are outstretched and fully extended (or near it depending on your comfort level), and inhale throughout the movement.
\n\nRepeat steps 3-4 for as many repetitions as are desired.</item>



    </string-array>
</resources>