<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="chest_head">

        <item>Push Ups</item>
        <item>Bench Press</item>
        <item>Incline Bench Press</item>
        <item>Decline Bench Press</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Press</item>
        <item>Incline Dumbbell Press</item>
        <item>Decline Dumbbell Press</item>
        <item>Dumbbell Flyes</item>
        <item>Incline Dumbbell Flyes</item>
        <item>Dumbbell PullOver</item>
        <item>Pec Dec</item>
        <item>Cable Cross Over</item>
        <item>Dips</item>


    </string-array>

    <string-array name="chest_content">


        <item>Adding weight to the classic exercise forces your muscles to work harder and keeps your rep range low enough that you’ll pack on serious muscle.
                Add load in the form of a plate, weight vest, or sandbag thrown over your back.\n\nDo it:\n\nAssume a pushup position wearing a weight vest or with a sandbag draped over your upper back or a weight plate balanced on your upper back.\n\nYour arms should be straight and hands slightly wider than your shoulders.\n\nBend at your elbows and lower your body until your chest nearly touches the floor.\n\nPause, and push your body back up.</item>


        <item>Adding chains or bands to the ends of a barbell makes it unstable.\n\nThe instability forces your core and stabilizer muscles to kick in to a higher degree, according to research conducted at the University of New England.
                That gives your chest a new stimulus, promoting strength.\n\n
        Do it:\nHang a chain over each end of the barbell, or anchor resistance bands to the bench and place them over each end of the bar.\n\nStart without weight, in order to get used to the unstable bar.
                \n\nGrab the barbell and lie on a bench.\n\nUsing an overhand grip that’s just beyond shoulder width, hold the bar above your sternum, keeping your arms straight.\n\nLower the bar to your chest, and then push it back to the starting position.</item>


        <item>Load the bar to an appropriate weight for your training.
              \n\nLay on the bench with your feet flat on the ground, driving through to your hips. Your back should be arched, and your shoulder blades retracted.
              \n\nTake a medium, pronated grip covering the rings on the bar. Remove the bar from the rack, holding the weight above your chest with your arms extended. This will be your starting position.
              \n\nLower the bar to the sternum by flexing the elbows. Maintain control and do not bounce the bar off of your chest. Your lats should stay tight and elbows slightly drawn in.
              \n\nAfter touching your torso with the bar, extend the elbows to return the bar to the starting position.</item>


        <item>Secure your legs at the end of the decline bench and slowly lay down on the bench.
              \n\nUsing a medium width grip (a grip that creates a 90-degree angle in the middle of the movement between the forearms and the upper arms), lift the bar from the rack and hold it straight over you with your arms locked. The arms should be perpendicular to the floor. This will be your starting position. Tip: In order to protect your rotator cuff, it is best if you have a spotter help you lift the barbell off the rack.
              \n\nAs you breathe in, come down slowly until you feel the bar on your lower chest.
              \n\nAfter a second pause, bring the bar back to the starting position as you breathe out and push the bar using your chest muscles. Lock your arms and squeeze your chest in the contracted position, hold for a second and then start coming down slowly again. Tip: It should take at least twice as long to go down than to come up).
              \n\nRepeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.
              \n\nWhen you are done, place the bar back in the rack.</item>


        <item>Lie on the bench with a dumbbell in each hand and your feet flat on the floor.
              \n\nYou can rest your feet up on the bench if it’s more comfortable.
              \n\nPush the dumbbells up so that your arms are directly over your shoulders and your palms are up.
              \n\nPull your abdominals in, and tilt your chin toward your chest.
              \n\nLower the dumbbells down and a little to the side until your elbows are slightly below your shoulders.
              \n\nRoll your shoulder blades back and down, like you’re pinching them together and accentuating your chest.
              \n\nPush the weights back up, taking care not to lock your elbows or allow your shoulder blades to rise off the bench.</item>


        <item>Pressing from an incline works the clavicular head of your chest Working that muscle—which resides high on your chest—gives your pecs extra pop.
            \n\nDo it:\nLie on a bench with the backrest set at a 45-degree incline.
            \n\nHold a pair of dumbbells above your chest with your arms straight and your palms turned toward your feet.
            \n\nLower the dumbbells to chest level, and then press them back up to the starting position.</item>


        <item>The exercise zeroes in on your lower chest, building serious size.
            \n\nDo it:\nLie on a decline bench with your shins hooked beneath the leg support.
            \n\nHold a pair of dumbbells above your chest with your arms straight.
            \n\nYour palms should face your feet and the weights should be just outside your shoulders.
            \n\nLower the dumbbells to your chest, pause, and then press them back up to the starting position.</item>


        <item>Lie down on a flat bench with a dumbbell on each hand resting on top of your thighs.
            \n\nThe palms of your hand will be facing each other.
            \n\nThen using your thighs to help raise the dumbbells, lift the dumbbells one at a time so you can hold them in front of you at shoulder width with the palms of your hands facing each other.
            \n\nRaise the dumbbells up like you\'re pressing them, but stop and hold just before you lock out. This will be your starting position.
              \n\nWith a slight bend on your elbows in order to prevent stress at the biceps tendon, lower your arms out at both sides in a wide arc until you feel a stretch on your chest.
            \n\nBreathe in as you perform this portion of the movement.Tip:Keep in mind that throughout the movement, the arms should remain stationary the movement should only occur at the shoulder joint.
              \n\nReturn your arms back to the starting position as you squeeze your chest muscles and breathe out. Tip: Make sure to use the same arc of motion used to lower the weights.
              \n\nHold for a second at the contracted position and repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Hold a dumbbell on each hand and lie on an incline bench that is set to an incline angle of no more than 30 degrees.
              \n\nExtend your arms above you with a slight bend at the elbows.
              \n\nNow rotate the wrists so that the palms of your hands are facing you. Tip: The pinky fingers should be next to each other. This will be your starting position.
              \n\nAs you breathe in, start to slowly lower the arms to the side while keeping the arms extended and while rotating the wrists until the palms of the hand are facing each other. Tip: At the end of the movement the arms will be by your side with the palms facing the ceiling.
              \n\nAs you exhale start to bring the dumbbells back up to the starting position by reversing the motion and rotating the hands so that the pinky fingers are next to each other again. Tip: Keep in mind that the movement will only happen at the shoulder joint and at the wrist. There is no motion that happens at the elbow joint.
              \n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions</item>


        <item>Step 1: Position a dumbbell standing up on a flat bench.
              \n\nStep 2: Making sure that the dumbbell stays in place on the top of the bench, lie perpendicular to it. Your torso should be across it, as if you were forming a cross with only your shoulders lying on its surface. Your hips will be positioned below the bench and your knees will be bent with your feet firmly placed on the floor. Your head will be off the bench as well.
              \n\nStep 3: Grab the dumbbell with both your hands and hold it straight over your chest with your elbows bent. Both of your palms should be pressing against the underside of one side of the dumbbell. This is your starting position.
              \n\nStep 4: Keeping your arms bent, lower the weight slowly in an arc behind your head. Inhale as you do so until you feel a stretch on your chest.
              \n\nStep 5: Next, bring the dumbbell back to the starting position using the same arc motion. Exhale while performing this movement.
              \n\nStep 6: Hold the dumbbell in the initial position for a second, then repeat the process for the desired number of reps.</item>


        <item>Step 1: Sit down on the bench and place your back flat against the back of the bench.
              \n\nStep 2: Position your forearms on the vertical pads with your hands gripping the provides handles. This is the starting position.
              \n\nStep 3: Begin exercise by squeezing your chest and bring your arms together so that they meet together out in front of your chest.
              \n\nStep 4: Reverse movement slowly back to starting position. Repeat as necessary.</item>


        <item>To get yourself into the starting position, place the pulleys on a high position (above your head), select the resistance to be used and hold the pulleys in each hand.
              \n\nStep forward in front of an imaginary straight line between both pulleys while pulling your arms together in front of you. Your torso should have a small forward bend from the waist. This will be your starting position.
              \n\nWith a slight bend on your elbows in order to prevent stress at the biceps tendon, extend your arms to the side (straight out at both sides) in a wide arc until you feel a stretch on your chest. Breathe in as you perform this portion of the movement. Tip: Keep in mind that throughout the movement, the arms and torso should remain stationary; the movement should only occur at the shoulder joint.
              \n\nReturn your arms back to the starting position as you breathe out. Make sure to use the same arc of motion used to lower the weights.
              \n\nHold for a second at the starting position and repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>For this exercise you will need access to parallel bars. To get yourself into the starting position, hold your body at arms length (arms locked) above the bars.
              \n\nWhile breathing in, lower yourself slowly with your torso leaning forward around 30 degrees or so and your elbows flared out slightly until you feel a slight stretch in the chest.
              \n\nOnce you feel the stretch, use your chest to bring your body back to the starting position as you breathe out. Tip: Remember to squeeze the chest at the top of the movement for a second.
              \n\nRepeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>