<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="legs_head">

    <item>Dumbbell Squart</item>
    <item>Dumbbell Clean</item>
    <item>Dumbbel Lungs</item>
    <item>Barbbell Lungs</item>
    <item>Leg Extension</item>
    <item>Leg Curl</item>
    <item>Squats Leg</item>
    <item>Goblet Squat</item>
    <item>Leg Press</item>
    <item>Seated Calf Raise</item>
        <item>Standing Calf Raises</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="legs_content">


        <item>Stand up straight while holding a dumbbell on each hand (palms facing the side of your legs).
\n\nPosition your legs using a shoulder width medium stance with the toes slightly pointed out. Keep your head up at all times as looking down will get you off balance and also maintain a straight back. This will be your starting position. Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall development; however you can choose any of the three stances discussed in the foot stances section.
\n\nBegin to slowly lower your torso by bending the knees as you maintain a straight posture with the head up. Continue down until your thighs are parallel to the floor. Tip: If you performed the exercise correctly, the front of the knees should make an imaginary straight line with the toes that is perpendicular to the front. If your knees are past that imaginary line (if they are past your toes) then you are placing undue stress on the knee and the exercise has been performed incorrectly.
\n\nBegin to raise your torso as you exhale by pushing the floor with the heel of your foot mainly as you straighten the legs again and go back to the starting position.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Preparation:Squat down with dumbbells near sides of ankles, palms facing together. Position shoulders over dumbbells with back arched tightly. Arms are straight with elbows pointed outward.
\n\nExecution:Pull dumbbells up off floor by extending hips and knees. As dumbbells reach knees vigorously, raise shoulders while keeping dumbbells close to thighs. Jump upward extending body. Shrug shoulders and pull dumbbells upward with arms, allowing elbows to bend out to sides, keeping dumbbells close to body. Aggressively pull body under dumbbell, rotating elbows around dumbbells. Catch dumbbells on shoulders while moving into squat position. Hitting bottom of squat, stand up immediately.
\n\nReturn:Lower dumbbells to mid-thigh position. With chest high and taut lower back, squat down into original position until dumbbells make contact with floor. Repeat.</item>


        <item>Stand with your torso upright holding two dumbbells in your hands by your sides. This will be your starting position.
\n\nStep forward with your right leg around 2 feet or so from the foot being left stationary behind and lower your upper body down, while keeping the torso upright and maintaining balance. Inhale as you go down. Note: As in the other exercises, do not allow your knee to go forward beyond your toes as you come down, as this will put undue stress on the knee joint. Make sure that you keep your front shin perpendicular to the ground.
\n\nUsing mainly the heel of your foot, push up and go back to the starting position as you exhale.
\n\nRepeat the movement for the recommended amount of repetitions and then perform with the left leg.</item>


        <item>This exercise is best performed inside a squat rack for safety purposes. To begin, first set the bar on a rack just below shoulder level. Once the correct height is chosen and the bar is loaded, step under the bar and place the back of your shoulders (slightly below the neck) across it.
\n\nHold on to the bar using both arms at each side and lift it off the rack by first pushing with your legs and at the same time straightening your torso.
\n\nStep away from the rack and step forward with your right leg and squat down through your hips, while keeping the torso upright and maintaining balance. Inhale as you go down. Note: Do not allow your knee to go forward beyond your toes as you come down, as this will put undue stress on the knee joint. li>
\n\nUsing mainly the heel of your foot, push up and go back to the starting position as you exhale.
\n\nRepeat the movement for the recommended amount of repetitions and then perform with the left leg.</item>


        <item>For this exercise you will need to use a leg extension machine. First choose your weight and sit on the machine with your legs under the pad (feet pointed forward) and the hands holding the side bars. This will be your starting position. Tip: You will need to adjust the pad so that it falls on top of your lower leg (just above your feet). Also, make sure that your legs form a 90-degree angle between the lower and upper leg. If the angle is less than 90-degrees then that means the knee is over the toes which in turn creates undue stress at the knee joint. If the machine is designed that way, either look for another machine or just make sure that when you start executing the exercise you stop going down once you hit the 90-degree angle.
\n\nUsing your quadriceps, extend your legs to the maximum as you exhale. Ensure that the rest of the body remains stationary on the seat. Pause a second on the contracted position.
\n\nSlowly lower the weight back to the original position as you inhale, ensuring that you do not go past the 90-degree angle limit.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of times.</item>


        <item>Adjust the machine lever to fit your height and lie face down on the leg curl machine with the pad of the lever on the back of your legs (just a few inches under the calves). Tip: Preferably use a leg curl machine that is angled as opposed to flat since an angled position is more favorable for hamstrings recruitment.
\n\nKeeping the torso flat on the bench, ensure your legs are fully stretched and grab the side handles of the machine. Position your toes straight (or you can also use any of the other two stances described on the foot positioning section). This will be your starting position.
\n\nAs you exhale, curl your legs up as far as possible without lifting the upper legs from the pad. Once you hit the fully contracted position, hold it for a second.
\n\nAs you inhale, bring the legs back to the initial position. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Position the barbell on the squat rack so that your upper chest and the barbell are at the same height.
\n\nBend your knees and place the bar above your body at the back of your shoulders.
\n\nposition your hands on the barbell at a distance more than the shoulder’s width.
\n\nNow push yourself upwards and straighten your legs and thereby pushing the barbell up. Now take one step forward.
\n\nStand with your legs apart, maintaining a distance of your shoulder’s width.
\n\nBending your knees, make your hips to bend too, giving an impression as if you are about to sit.
\n\nKeep on moving down until your knees come parallel to the ground or even to more. Make sure, the knees are pointing in the same direction as your feet.
\n\nNow pause in this position to the count of one.
\n\nCome back to the initial/starting position by making your hips and knees straight.
\n\nMake any amendments to your stance or grip before carrying on with the next rep</item>


        <item>Stand holding a light kettlebell by the horns close to your chest. This will be your starting position.
\n\nSquat down between your legs until your hamstrings are on your calves. Keep your chest and head up and your back straight.
\n\nAt the bottom position, pause and use your elbows to push your knees out. Return to the starting position, and repeat for 10-20 repetitions.</item>


        <item>Using a leg press machine, sit down on the machine and place your legs on the platform directly in front of you at a medium (shoulder width) foot stance. (Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall development; however you can choose any of the three stances described in the foot positioning section).
\n\nLower the safety bars holding the weighted platform in place and press the platform all the way up until your legs are fully extended in front of you. Tip: Make sure that you do not lock your knees. Your torso and the legs should make a perfect 90-degree angle. This will be your starting position.
\n\nAs you inhale, slowly lower the platform until your upper and lower legs make a 90-degree angle.
\n\nPushing mainly with the heels of your feet and using the quadriceps go back to the starting position as you exhale.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions and ensure to lock the safety pins properly once you are done. You do not want that platform falling on you fully loaded.</item>


        <item>Sit on the machine and place your toes on the lower portion of the platform provided with the heels extending off. Choose the toe positioning of your choice (forward, in, or out) as per the beginning of this chapter.
\n\nPlace your lower thighs under the lever pad, which will need to be adjusted according to the height of your thighs. Now place your hands on top of the lever pad in order to prevent it from slipping forward.
\n\nLift the lever slightly by pushing your heels up and release the safety bar. This will be your starting position.
\n\nSlowly lower your heels by bending at the ankles until the calves are fully stretched. Inhale as you perform this movement.
\n\nRaise the heels by extending the ankles as high as possible as you contract the calves and breathe out. Hold the top contraction for a second.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>


        <item>Adjust the padded lever of the calf raise machine to fit your height.
\n\nPlace your shoulders under the pads provided and position your toes facing forward (or using any of the two other positions described at the beginning of the chapter). The balls of your feet should be secured on top of the calf block with the heels extending off it. Push the lever up by extending your hips and knees until your torso is standing erect. The knees should be kept with a slight bend; never locked. Toes should be facing forward, outwards or inwards as described at the beginning of the chapter. This will be your starting position.
\n\nRaise your heels as you breathe out by extending your ankles as high as possible and flexing your calf. Ensure that the knee is kept stationary at all times. There should be no bending at any time. Hold the contracted position by a second before you start to go back down.
\n\nGo back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in by lowering your heels as you bend the ankles until calves are stretched.
\n\nRepeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.</item>



    </string-array>
</resources>