<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="stretching_name">
        <item>1.Standing Hamstring Stretch</item>
        <item>2.Piriformis Stretch</item>
        <item>3.Lunge With Spinal Twist</item>
        <item>4.Triceps Stretch</item>
        <item>5.Figure Four Stretch</item>
        <item>6.90/90 Stretch</item>
        <item>7.Frog Stretch</item>
        <item>8.Butterfly Stretch</item>
        <item>9.Seated Shoulder Squeeze</item>
        <item>10.Side Bend Stretch</item>
        <item>11.Lunging Hip Flexor Stretch</item>
        <item>12.Lying Pectoral Stretch</item>
        <item>13.Knee to Chest Stretch</item>
        <item>14.Seated Neck Release</item>
        <item>15.Lying Quad Stretch</item>
        <item>16.Sphinx Pose</item>
        <item>17.Extended Puppy Pose</item>
        <item>18.Pretzel Stretch</item>
        <item>19.Reclining Bound Angle Pose</item>
        <item>20.Standing Quad Stretch</item>
        <item>21.Knees to Chest</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="stretching_content">
        <item>Stand tall with your feet hip-width apart, knees slightly bent, arms by your sides.
\n\nExhale as you bend forward at the hips, lowering your head toward floor, while keeping your head, neck and shoulders relaxed.
\n\nWrap your arms around backs of your legs and hold anywhere from 45 seconds to two minutes.
\n\nBend your knees and roll up when you\'re done.
  </item>

        <item>Sit on the floor with both legs extended in front of you.
\n\nCross your right leg over your left, and place your right foot flat on the floor.
\n\nPlace your right hand on the floor behind your body.
\n\nPlace your left hand on your right quad or your left elbow on your right knee (as shown) and press your right leg to the left as you twist your torso to the right.
\n\nIf the spinal rotation bothers your back, take it out and simply use your left hand to pull your right quad in and to the left.</item>
        <item>Start standing with your feet together.
\n\nTake a big step forward with your left foot, so that you are in a staggered stance.
\n\nBend your left knee and drop into a lunge, keeping your right leg straight behind you with your toes on the ground, so you feel a stretch at the front of your right thigh
           \n\n Place your right hand on the floor and twist your upper body to the left as you extend your left arm toward the ceiling.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nRepeat on the other side.</item>
        <item>Kneel, sit, or stand tall with feet hip-width apart, arms extended overhead.
\n\nBend your right elbow and reach your right hand to touch the top middle of your back.
\n\nReach your left hand overhead and grasp just below your right elbow.
\n\nGently pull your right elbow down and toward your head.
\n\nSwitch arms and repeat.</item>
        <item>Lie on your back with your feet flat on the floor.
\n\nCross your left foot over your right quad.
\n\nLift your right leg off the floor. Grab onto the back of your right leg and gently pull it toward your chest.
\n\nWhen you feel a comfortable stretch, hold there.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nSwitch sides and repeat.</item>
        <item>Let your leg rest flat on the floor.
\n\nPlace your left knee to the left of your body, and bend the knee so that your foot faces behind you. Keep your left foot flexed.
\n\nKeep your right butt cheek on the floor. Try to move the left cheek as close to the floor as possible. It may not be possible if you\'re super tight.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nRepeat on the other side.</item>
        <item>Start on all fours.
\n\nSlide your knees wider than shoulder-width apart.
\n\nTurn your toes out and rest the inner edges of your feet flat on the floor.
\n\nShift your hips back toward your heels.
\n\nMove from your hands to your forearms to get a deeper stretch, if possible.
\n\nHold for for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
        <item>Sit tall on the floor with the soles of your feet together, knees bent out to sides.
\n\nHold onto your ankles or feet, engage your abs, and slowly lower your body toward your feet as far as you can while pressing your knees toward the floor.
\n\nIf you\'re too tight to bend over, simply press your knees down.
\n\nHold this stretch for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
        <item>Sit on the floor with your knees bent and feet flat on the floor.
\n\nClasp your hands behind your lower back.
\n\nStraighten and extend your arms and squeeze your shoulder blades together.
\n\nDo this for 3 seconds, and then release. Repeat 5 to 10 times.</item>
        <item>Kneel on the floor with your legs together, back straight, and core tight.
\n\nExtend your left leg out to the side. Keep it perpendicular to your body (not in front or behind you).
\n\nExtend your right arm overhead, rest your left arm on your left leg, and gently bend your torso and right arm to the left side.
\n\nKeep your hips facing forward.
\n\nHold this stretch for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nRepeat on the other side.</item>
        <item>Kneel on your left knee. Place your right foot flat on the floor in front of you, knee bent.
\n\nLean forward, stretching your left hip toward the floor.
\n\nSqueeze your butt; this will allow you to stretch your hip flexor even more.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nSwitch sides and repeat.</item>
        <item>Lie on your stomach with both arms extended to the sides so your body is in a T shape.
\n\nPush off the ground with your left hand and bend your left knee for balance as you start to roll to your right side. You should feel this in your right-side pectoral muscles.
\n\nAs your mobility increases, you\'ll be able to stretch further and roll your body further.
\n\nRepeat on the other side.</item>
        <item>Lie on your back with both legs extended.
\n\nPull your right knee into your chest, while keeping the left leg straight and your lower back pressed into the floor.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nRepeat on the other leg.</item>
        <item>Stand with feet shoulder-width apart, or sit down with your back straight and chest lifted.
\n\nDrop your left ear to your left shoulder.
\n\nTo deepen the stretch, gently press down on your head with your left hand.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
        <item>Lie on one side.
\n\nKeep your bottom leg straight and bend your top knee so your foot is by your butt.
\n\nHold your top foot with your hand, pulling it toward your butt.
\n\nKeep your hips stable so you\'re not rocking back as you pull.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nSwitch sides and repeat.</item>
        <item>Lie on your stomach with your legs straight out behind you.
\n\nPlace your elbows under your shoulders and your forearms on the floor as you lift your chest up off the floor.
\n\nPress your hips and thighs into the floor, and think about lengthening your spine while keeping your shoulders relaxed.
\n\nSit up just enough to feel a nice stretch in your lower back. Don\'t hyperextend, and stop immediately if you start to feel any discomfort or pain.</item>
        <item>Start on all fours.
\n\nWalk your arms forward a few inches and curl your toes under.
\n\nPush your hips up and back halfway toward your heels.
\n\nPush through the palms of your hands to keep your arms straight and engaged.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
        <item>Lie on your left side with your head resting on your arm.
\n\nBend your right knee and hip up toward your chest as far as you can, and let it drop to the floor.
\n\nBend your left knee and grab your left foot (use a strap if you can\’t reach it) with your right hand.
\n\nMake sure your leg and torso remain in a straight line as you gently bring your top shoulder blade toward the floor.
\n\nFor more of a spinal twist, turn your head to look over your right shoulder.</item>
        <item>This is an excellent stretch to do both as a gentle warm-up and at the end of a workout as a releasing pose.
            \n\n"Due to the passive nature of the posture, it can and should be adjusted based on how the body is feeling to encourage the proper stretch and release."
            \n\nHe suggests using pillows or a rolled up towels as bolsters under your knees if you need the support at first.
\n\nLie on your back.
\n\nBring the soles of your feet together and allow your knees to open up and move closer to the floor.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
        <item>Stand with your feet together.
\n\nBend your left knee and use your left hand to pull your left foot toward your butt. Keep your knees together.
\n\nIf you need to, put one hand on a wall for balance.
\n\nSqueeze your glutes to increase the stretch in the front of your legs.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.
\n\nRepeat on the other leg.</item>
        <item>Lie on your back and pull your knees into your chest with both hands.
\n\nKeep your lower back on the floor.
\n\nHold for 30 seconds to 2 minutes.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>